<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal</title>
    <link>https://dlozanof.github.io/cc-nightmare-wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dlozanof.github.io/cc-nightmare-wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design document</title>
      <link>https://dlozanof.github.io/cc-nightmare-wiki/docs/design_document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dlozanof.github.io/cc-nightmare-wiki/docs/design_document/</guid>
      <description>Executive Manager (reverse-funded) contract Future dystopia in which Corporate wants to get resource from across the galaxy. This is you, an executive junior manager, doing a reverse-funded internship for VA Incorporated TM:
As many others, you are in charge of extracting all resources of interest from your assigned planet. To do so you will define rewards for tasks that can be accomplished, and the people corporate will migrate there will work on them.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-manager-reverse-funded-contract&#34;&gt;Executive Manager (reverse-funded) contract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future dystopia in which Corporate wants to get resource from across the galaxy. This is you, an executive junior manager, doing a reverse-funded internship for VA Incorporated TM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;./intro_img.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hello Friend&#34;  class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;    /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As many others, you are in charge of extracting all resources of interest from your assigned planet. To do so you will define rewards for tasks that can be accomplished, and the people corporate will migrate there will work on them. These rewards are the only way they can keep living there! These so-called Corporate Citizens are born under contract, and their lifespan is directly associated to their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate knows this is a daunting task, and provides &amp;ldquo;Drunkyards TM&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Weaponize.ME TM&amp;rdquo; buildings within your base. These are the main ways of getting  entertainment and equipment for the CC living in the planet, so they will be able to grow and be more profitable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great news, since if you do not reach the objectives you will be terminated as per clause V.12.3 section 3 paragraph 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;📜&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    ... and other causes of termination Failure to fulfill objectives...
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we do not expect this to happen to you! We would never hire lazy people that does not put the Company over everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day you will define rewards for different available missions, and the CC living in your base will take upon them depending on the reward/risk ratio. Risk depends on the individual/group of CC which will partake on the mission, as it is relative to their abilities and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the beginning most missions will be of scouting the planet, trying to find the areas with the most profitable resources, of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🧠&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Did you know? Average Managers are said to enjoy a lot the innards of certain xenofrogs which only live in sector Alpha-32. It was a junior just like you who found this and lived a prosperous life! Not only she lived to the old age of 34, she even got a yearly vacation day off!).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know we are not alone in the galaxy, but we are much less alone in this planet. There is flora and fauna which does not like to be plundered, so scouting and harvesting are not the only things to do during a mission. Our CC are trained in combat and will face these dangers to the best of their ability. This does not mean success in 100% (nor 20%) of cases, but do not falter. Others will come to take their place soon!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./map_view.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Map view&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;right&#34;  style=&#34;color: red;&#34; &gt;here you see an overview of the resources and available missions in every sector&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Specifically, a mission will have a reward (defined by you) and certain risk factors (flora/fauna, weather, environment) which are palliated by expertise and equipment of CC. This ratio is then compared with the necessities of the CC and if the outcome is good enough, the CC will take on the mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he does, you will get a notification and will receive a report once it is finished (one way or another). This include what happened in every stage and the resources/objectives that were achieved. Finally if the mission is successful a certain amount of credits will be deducted from your loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These resources are your lifeblood, are directly sent to Corporate HQ for further processing and a certain amount of credits will be added to your balance. You can use them to pay off your loan or to invest them into improving your base. This mostly means better equipment for your CC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: In the map view you can construct mining bases which provide certain inflow of resources daily. They can be assaulted by fauna so missions to clear them up can be created. Maybe long term missions with daily cost to operate them?? -&amp;gt; Not a lot of sense since this is pretty much a long `gather` mission. But possible.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;market&#34;&gt;Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a dynamic market in which prices fluctuate every week. It does not make sense to gather adamantite when the market is overflown with it, but lacking &amp;ldquo;wood&amp;rdquo;. Or maybe you can just not sell the resources and wait for a better moment. As long as you have the funds to do this, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the market indicates the best resource to get for maximum profit. Then in the mission tab you can filter available missions by resources that can be obtained and focus on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;missions&#34;&gt;Missions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some aspects generals to all missions is that they all can be successful or a failure. If it fails it means the risk was too high for the CC to take on, and he tried to go back to base. A small mishap might mean a horde of xenos ganking up on the CC so this is not always possible and he will be decommissioned as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case the reward is not provided of course, but fret not, CC got the best rewards of all: experience! Learning from past mistakes is a valuable asset, is it not? And we are talking about literal experience points, avoidance/scout related skill will be improved so the survival rate of future missions will be even higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mission success experience is also granted, but related to the mission at hand. In &lt;code&gt;gather&lt;/code&gt; missions the gathering-related skills are the ones that are improved.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./mission_view.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Mission view&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;right&#34;  style=&#34;color: red;&#34; &gt;Here you can see details of all available missions&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise stated, a mission consists on several phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel to POI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return from POI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During each of these phases some events can happen, and are reported independently of the other phases. After the mission is finished a report is generated with the following structure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel to POI
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 1 - Uneventful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 2 - Xeno ambush
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 3 - Uneventful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute mission
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 4 - Uneventful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return from POI
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 5 - Uneventful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 6 - Uneventful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 7 - Crew fight ???&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see some missions can take a long time, so plan ahead objective-wise. If you depend on the success of several long-term missions and some of them fail you are in for trouble!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: I&amp;#39;m not sure yet if I want to have more-than-1-day-length missions.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also note that the time to reach/come back from a POI depends on the distance to it, and can be alleviated by using improved means of transport if you get to unblock them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: Teleporter building which you can set in sectors so CC can start their travel from there. You of course have to maintain them if xenos attack.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scout&#34;&gt;Scout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many kind of missions. But to access them you need to know about your environment (how do you plan to gather minerals without locating them first?). Scout missions increase the &lt;code&gt;Scouted&lt;/code&gt; percentage of a sector. If it reaches 100% it means it has been completely explored and there is nothing else to find there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing the &lt;code&gt;Scouted&lt;/code&gt; percentage unblocks missions in the sector. It means your scouts found points of interests within, and then you can assign missions related to them. For example if a mineral vein is found a &lt;code&gt;Gather&lt;/code&gt; mission can be created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate is not blind however, and has a basic idea of what is on the planet (they would never send you to explore a random planet, after all. You cost money. Almost.) This means that you know the biome and geography of the different sectors, so you know what to expect. I just expect you do not try to find minerals in the sea. (wtf, this is probably valid). Specifically for every sector you know beforehand which resources you can expect to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sector S4 [Scouted 30%]
Risk rating: LOW/MED/HIGH
Can find: Rocks, Wood, Ore, Domgles, Hoferters
Available: Wood [LW/MD/RICH]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of a scouting mission can be a success or a failure (escape / death of scout) depending on the ratio between the risk rating and the scout&amp;rsquo;s abilities. A successful mission might yield the location of new POIs which in turn yield more kind of missions; it will always (even in failure????) increase the &lt;code&gt;scouted %&lt;/code&gt; so future missions have higher probability of yielding POIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gather&#34;&gt;Gather&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sector S5
Risk rating: LOW/MED/HIGH
Gather resource: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt; Wood &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;   &amp;laquo;&amp;lt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; allows to select the desired resource????&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one I am not so clear how to define how many resources should yield. I think it should increase with &lt;code&gt;gatherer&lt;/code&gt; skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idea 1&lt;/strong&gt;
Divide the &lt;code&gt;execution day&lt;/code&gt; into hours, and every hour should have a % of combat, diminishing the gathering of that hour. This is not great since could completely break a long expedition in the first hour if combat is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idea 2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; mission purpose is pretty much to clear enemies in this POI so the risk rating goes down, increasing yield of &lt;code&gt;gather&lt;/code&gt; mission. A very simplified formula would be
$$ yield = CC_{number}\cdot 1/enemise \cdot gather_{skill} \cdot 10   $$
Risk rating does not automatically involve actual combat, but represents the bothersome presence of hostiles in the area. CCs have to do evasive maneuvers and hide from them to keep working in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, combat is still possible. It affects gathering yield by removing some amount of the yield. On the other hand, combat skills are improved and xeno materials are &amp;ldquo;gathered&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CCs that specialize in gathering can acquire equipment that improves their skills, helps avoiding enemies or other kind of benefits. All this in the end results in increased yield. For the same reward! CCs are nothing if not proud of a joob well done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pest-control&#34;&gt;Pest control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is quite simple. Most POIs (if not all) have some kind of hostiles lurking around and making difficult (if not impossible) to work there. Some CC teams/individuals specialize in clearing these areas so other teams can &lt;code&gt;gather&lt;/code&gt; in peace at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least one combat round is guaranteed, but if there are more hostiles in the area more combat rounds can happen. Depends on how the CCs feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: I am still to decide how to model hostiles. The main idea is that there are sort of `clans` that control certain areas. This can be very complicated or very simple and I am not sure where I want to stand.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sure a quantifiable amount of hostiles must be there to maken sense of the combat report. Ill leave the discussion to Hostile Modeling section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;investigate&#34;&gt;Investigate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one and &lt;code&gt;terminate&lt;/code&gt; are sort of related. Could also be related to the hostiles modeling in the world. Point is that some POIs could be different than just places where to get resources, and by investigating them could unblock other set of more particular missions. Just to spice things a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: I am currently thinking of, which could connect many dots, is that you can locate nests of hostiles or alpha ones which can be `terminated`. This particular mission is detailed later, but the main consequence is that the risk level of several *sectors*  is reduced. Or completely removed.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: Related to the teleporter idea, maybe you cannot build buildings unless you really remove the hostile `clan`. How would you send construction workers if there is an active and territorial set of hostiles in the area??
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: Another option would be to find alien artifacts. Corporate contacts you about the possibility and you need to explore certain areas to find and retrieve it. Sort of a long term quest.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;terminate&#34;&gt;Terminate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; is done to remove average hostiles. &lt;code&gt;Terminate&lt;/code&gt; is to really remove the source of them, and the risk level is completely off the charts (and so CC&amp;rsquo;s expect the rewards to be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of them as Bosses. The effect of clearing them out should be different than just a big &lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; mission. There can be some smaller ones that are blocking our access to some resources, and big ones that would remove the threat level in the sectors the &lt;code&gt;clan&lt;/code&gt; control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;world-modeling&#34;&gt;World modeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section I detail how xeno lifeforms behave in their planets. On map generation certain &lt;code&gt;clan&lt;/code&gt;s will be generated and part of the map assigned as it&amp;rsquo;s territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: There is flora and fauna. Fauna is actual hostiles you need to combat (even if they are tree-based lifeforms. Flora is an orthogonal concept that represents another layer of dangers. They are also hostile and can be removed with exterminate missions, like poison-emitting flowers. `exterminate` mission could remove part of this threat.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: This could be low-danger at first, but expand over time and grow more dangerous if left unchecked!. This would mean the map view could have a `POI` view, a `Creatures` view and a `Flora` view.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not 100% of the map has to be part of the territory, and it cannot be shared with other clans. This is in addition to the biome, so a certain area on the map has:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A biome that defines it. Glaciar/rocks/lava/highlands/etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A flora that matches it. Frozen roses are not found in lava biome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of creature territories that matches the biome. Fire golems in lava for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./hostile_modeling_1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hostile modeling&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;right&#34;  style=&#34;color: red;&#34; &gt;Map generation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Notice that the image does not show the flora, but is also present in a different layer. Taking everything into account any one sector (character in the terminal) has the following properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sector name: ZC-45
Biome: Glaciar
Flora: None/Fozen roses
Creatures: Yetis (why the fuck not) [HIGH]
Base risk rating: 0 + 10 (yetis HIGH) + 5 (roses)
Weather: sunny/raining/acid blood rain &amp;lt;&amp;lt; This is hidden, randomly decided when CCs arrive at the scene.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;HIGH&lt;/code&gt; indicates the density of the creature population. CC&amp;rsquo;s in &lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; missions will do their best to find a pack of creatures they can take on. However the density will limit the minimum/maximum size of the packs they will be able to find. These numbers depends on the characteristics of the creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a &lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; mission is created for this sector, the CC&amp;rsquo;s stack will be used to generate the ratio between risk rating and CC&amp;rsquo;s abilities (taking equipment into account). Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CC Information
Name: Yisus

Skills:
   - Melee: 5
   - Ranged: 10
   - Subterfuge: 6
   - Perception: 5

Equipment:
   - Light armor: Defense + 1
   - Jetboots: Defense + 1, Escape + 4
   - AK-48: Ranged + 5
   - Trenchcoat: Cold resistance + 3, Subterfuge + 1
   - Heat fingerprint detector: Perception + 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Yisus&lt;/code&gt; combat rating is &lt;code&gt;10 (ranged) + 5 (AK-48) = 15&lt;/code&gt;. On the &lt;code&gt;pest control&lt;/code&gt; mission in the sector detailed some lines ago the risk rating is 15, so the ration is &lt;code&gt;15 / 15 = 1.0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: Biomes can define certain resistance minimums required to enter in them. For example glacier ones would require `cold resistance` of at least 10
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means he&amp;rsquo;s not in favour nor against the idea of taking on this mission (asumming he actually have equipment to go into the glaciar). This is compared agains their neccesities and the rest of missions; possibly undertaking it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;combat-modeling---alternative-1&#34;&gt;Combat Modeling - Alternative 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is automatic and every CC and creature will behave in its own interest. The way I see it whenever a combat happens there is a &lt;code&gt;combat field&lt;/code&gt; divided in 6 slots:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;| Team 1                               | Team 2
| Long range | Mid range | Melee range | Melee range | Mid range | Long range
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;CC&amp;rsquo;s position depends on preferred weapon equipment. For example a CC with a sniper rifle (and good long range combat stats, I hope) will be on it&amp;rsquo;s own team &lt;code&gt;Long range&lt;/code&gt; segment. &lt;code&gt;Yeti&lt;/code&gt;s creatures will, on the other hand, prefer to be on the &lt;code&gt;Melee range&lt;/code&gt; segment of their team. Actual combat positions however depend on how the combat was initiated. Depending on who has the initiative the positioning will benefit the one which initiated combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: It is actually a bit more complicated than that. Every time a combat is randomly decided to happen, there is a check of `perception` vs `subterfuge` on both sides of the combat. If one team detects the other but not the other way around, the first team will have the initiative. Otherwise if both fail or both pass the combat will begin in `nominal` conditions (that is, without benefit for either party).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat is divided in several phases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initiative phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are explained below in detail, but basically combat starts with an &lt;code&gt;initiative phase&lt;/code&gt; that determines the situation in the &lt;code&gt;combat field&lt;/code&gt;. Then several &lt;code&gt;combat phase&lt;/code&gt; are suceeded in which each creature takes an action, and when there are no more units in one side a &lt;code&gt;survival&lt;/code&gt; phase determines is KO&amp;rsquo;ed creatures were able to escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initiative-phase&#34;&gt;Initiative phase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s remember our friend &lt;code&gt;Yisus&lt;/code&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s say he is a &lt;code&gt;Mid range&lt;/code&gt; specialist (because of the AK-48) and that he is hunting for some Yetis. He passes near a group of Yetis (x2), thus initiating a initiative calculation stage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Initiative phase:
=================

CC detects Yetis?
  - CC&amp;#39;s perception: 5 (skill) + 5 (heat fingerprint detector) = 10 vs
  - Yeti subterfuge: 6 (Skill) = 6
Yetis detect CCs?
  - CC&amp;#39;s subterfuge: 6 (skill) + 1 (trenchcoat) = 7 vs
  - Yeti perception: 5 (skill) = 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possible results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CC detect yetis
Yetis do not detect CC
| Team 1                               | Team 2
| Long range | Mid range | Melee range | Melee range | Mid range | Long range
               Yisus                                   Yeti

CC detect yetis
Yetis detect CC
| Team 1                               | Team 2
| Long range | Mid range | Melee range | Melee range | Mid range | Long range
               Yisus                     Yeti

Yetis detect CC
CC does not detect CC
| Team 1                               | Team 2
| Long range | Mid range | Melee range | Melee range | Mid range | Long range
                           Yisus         Yeti
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last one sucks real bad for our CC, since he can only use weapons befitting the combat segment he&amp;rsquo;s in. So a secondary weapon (knife perhaps) would be used with its own Melee stats, which are not great at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: Maybe this is too harsh. Potentially destroying the concept of mid/long range except for very particular archetipes or forcing teams instead of individuals for baseline gameplay. Reducing stats in Melee range maybe?
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: Other option is to make ranged weapons much stronger than melee ones, so the creatures power are expected to be quite low by the time Melee comat arrives.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: A more complicated way to handle this is to have some `tactics` that can be used. For example kiting the creatures. If ranged unit is in melee it tries to disengange and shot with a penalty in damage. OOR maybe that could be the behavior in melee. Try to disengange just enough to get some shots in, and if it fails use Melee attack. This is neat since could mean SKILLS on lvl up (increased disengange possibility, etc)
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;combat-phase&#34;&gt;Combat phase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point combat begins, and after several rounds only one victor remains (and some defeated units could potentially have scaped instead).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;✨&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Random idea: On the beginning I was thinking that escaping would be a different phase, but instead it could just be a survival check after a unit is defeated. In this sense defeat is not killing but receiving enough damage that the unit deems success impossible and tries to escape.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat rounds are simple. Axioms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is resolved at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every unit takes only one valid &lt;code&gt;combat action&lt;/code&gt; between the ones available to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every unit has a &lt;code&gt;danger level&lt;/code&gt; and the higher it is, the more the enemies will focus on that unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeting itself is a bit more complicated. Every unit has a &lt;code&gt;danger level&lt;/code&gt;, and the higher it is the more likely it will be designated as target by all the enemy units that can target it. But other factors are also taken into account (remaining HP for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: There would be actually just one `preferred target rating`, given by an equation depending of every monster. Yetis are simple, but other ones could have low HP and low damage, but do area damage so the danger rating should increase with the number of CCs.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important!:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every field sector units can only take offensive actions targeting enemies in certain sectors of the opposing side:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Melee can only target melee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mid range can target melee and mid range&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long range can target all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;combat-actions&#34;&gt;Combat actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on top of a previous &lt;code&gt;designer though&lt;/code&gt; regarding skills&amp;hellip; In every &lt;code&gt;combat phase&lt;/code&gt; creatures take one of the many available actions. There are 4 basic ones and more advanced ones depending on the skill level of the CC (and creatures have its own particular ones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: I was thinking about having levels, and skills for CC of level 3 for example. But maybe is more interesting that having Subterfuge &amp;gt;= 10 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Ranged combat &amp;gt;= 10 unlocks `Sniper shot`, a special attack that does x3 damage and has 2 rounds of cooldown
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;melee-attack&#34;&gt;Melee attack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requires attacker and defender to be in &lt;code&gt;Melee range&lt;/code&gt; section of the combat field. Attacker uses &lt;code&gt;Melee attack&lt;/code&gt; skill and defender &lt;code&gt;Melee defense&lt;/code&gt; skill. Damage is given by attacker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Strength&lt;/code&gt; and any bonus the weapong provides. Armor might provide damage reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ranged-attack&#34;&gt;Ranged attack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly the same as melee attack, but using &lt;code&gt;Long/Mid range&lt;/code&gt; skill vs &lt;code&gt;Range defense&lt;/code&gt; skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: Not sure if I should create a Long range defense and mid range defense skills. Does not seem to have a lot of sense to me, to be honest.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disengage&#34;&gt;Disengage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This skill is used by ranged creatures when they are in melee combat situation. I need to decide between two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always succeeds, so they receive a free melee attack but they move back, and the next turn they have a free ranged attack while the hostiles move towards them again. In a cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is actually a melee attack of sorts, does not do a lot of damage but if successful CC is moved back one sector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove it alltogether, every CC is mostly melee but has additional benefit of ranged weapons during initial phases. I do not like this one too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: Maybe removing the `mid range` sector would be an improvement, so that snipers can disengage to their allocated sector. Melee enemies do not receive two attacks on the beginning (they will from a skill maybe), but in exchange snipers can attack once every two rounds after melee starts.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;charge&#34;&gt;Charge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed for melee units. The unit moves forward one space. If it cannot move forward it will &amp;ldquo;move&amp;rdquo; the enemy field forward. This is a bit weird because it means the friendly units in far slots will be &amp;ldquo;teleported&amp;rdquo; forward. This is a design decision to take. I would need to try and see if I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;combat-modeling---alternative-2&#34;&gt;Combat Modeling - Alternative 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is quite more complicated, but also more interesting. &lt;code&gt;initiative phase&lt;/code&gt; is same as in the first alternative, but then the combat actually happens in a map. Inspiration based on many roguelike games, but specifically &lt;strong&gt;Caves of Qud&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./caves_of_qud.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hostile modeling&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;right&#34;  style=&#34;color: red;&#34; &gt;Combat report/video&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;An example of combat:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PbGn7Ej_ui4?start=130&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that the combat is actually recorded via a drone, and can be replayed to see what happened. This idea has been taken from &lt;strong&gt;Dominions 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OWQqQ058iKA?list=PLl3YYe6_JF4t0J_vgwULrDO6HnzO6HFnu&amp;amp;start=122&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game&amp;rsquo;s log is not so great, and neither are the controls for skipping forward. I would like to improve upon them, but on the other hand there is not a huge need for detail since the player will never have power over what is going to happen during the combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initiative-phase-1&#34;&gt;Initiative phase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is virtually the same as the alternative 1, but in this case since there is an actual map instead of &lt;code&gt;slots&lt;/code&gt; we talk about &lt;code&gt;distances&lt;/code&gt;. Ranged units will want to start the combat as further away from the enemy as the range of their weapon permits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;combat-phase-1&#34;&gt;Combat phase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your tipically roguelike combat, but everything is automated. This would potentially require some special abilities like &lt;code&gt;sprint&lt;/code&gt; to avoid melee in all cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many kinds of reports while a mission is ongoing, but the most in depth one is the combat report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;combat-reports&#34;&gt;Combat reports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several events that trigger a combat, and the results of it will be reported to your desk at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  #callout {
    background: #32303f;
    padding: 1.5em 1.25em;
    border-radius: 3px;
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: row;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
  }
  #callout-inner {
    margin-left: 1em;
  }
  @media (max-width: 767px) {
    #callout {
    padding: 1.5em 0.75em 1.5em 0.6em;
    }
    #callout-inner {
      margin-left: 0.5em;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;callout&#34; style=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;🔧&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    Designer though: When to make the reports available? I would say that by the end of the missions so all of them appear together.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The log is not great, but the point is that battles happen and the player can see how it played out after the fact. And is quite nice to actually &lt;strong&gt;see&lt;/strong&gt; what happened every turn; but in &lt;code&gt;CC-nightmare&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s case there would be nice controls for stepping through turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ref: https://asciiflow.com/#/share/eJzV2M1q20AQB%2FBXGYRVBIkQlFIan9zSkmMPvRkdVqQ%2BBFwfJBc2hEApPfbQg6F9mD6Nn6QrraSdmZ3dVcih5I9iZJtIv8x%2BKvfZofmyy9aHr%2Fv9ZbZv7nZtts7u60zX2frq1dVlnd2Zs5dvXpuz404fzZs6O59%2Bnk%2Ffnu3xC0zOp7%2FP%2Bqjrw%2Fn0HfxorYVPxYwXMFfbwnbIC5z5iqBszOlGCuZc75ub26Z1GiKTInGG6K2AsRorWsDhxUGYQFHmLzhnK3G0VlNA6Q0MAPwa4yBDpM3GEnHOwOhs0PVmjPnZaAJJcsTTAMhxzr9%2F%2BIezWV3%2FO4pko6GXLcTRfjSdsc42fx3DdST2YrhoPW0OCDTt3c5vrGDpHkHjBbNvpS7vqoYHlE%2FREd2jqmaaVAFQHCihs7EG9cf8gtpFe1vHU1VTpVzRLAqILTaFChjfbd%2FJMO2xjKtCragci1YtyrIEoYDedMpZuixFEo1ijZeev%2FAMluj6hFT2SYOqShK5kZgaepHOhkFlKXkETVUJww%2BPPnzrwG1DX3iccgFH8KDmQn%2B7u%2Bm7t58%2BLPD4nDKtETyk90z3inWUFEeVJReFMKZHxzvz6ElM2XEO9uAAFEXBOcajw5zR8zRO0FO4DJiiIEtdPzfxoY49123Tdfvm8LnDd05wIOjBnDF0uVPgcSZPeBETP8Ucs2qJHF%2FDOUr5E%2BHUnQPr1iKOVCBBU0wrB6zGCPPy7JGW%2FkDNaGMNWcIpoN9%2F53ke49DVQdrzRzikLzBNa0M4%2BZAIJ9JxMDJcHRj3PIBKBC2OcYycPCcecRGNeWZJ4BHJjpB5Q0EZLa9PnlNPYE1fuGYJ24zRAbNJBHmaBCe0TxSrpWl1wBao90CoQFwT54TGufyZ5o01vkzDWObk%2BXKO7Am0oWYDHcBZAu3FNTrBkXamE%2Bf9rtu1RyznnGnSB%2FvG81yYaL84EY5ECjYhmwb50w3zXEzhmgTHM0lzIX3gwQh0Kmpm0ErifLzZNYcgCeO8faywSChSJpA1FrQSOdFID18OJvcdVx1QAYwJrHzO6X%2F%2FS%2FIpx5%2BxFM%2F6qLOH7OEfUSxmQA%3D%3D)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
